331 Queen's Park Junction, BN2 9XL Brighton, United Kingdom Phone: +44 (0) 1273 877 418 E-mail: M.Bianco@sussex.ac.uk

Website: https://micbia.github.io/

I am a second-year PhD student, part of the Reionization group lead by Prof. Ilian T. Iliev, in the Astronomy Centre at the University of Sussex. I am very keen on solving problems with a scientific approach and I have a particular interest in numerical simulation and statistical analysis. My best traits are versatility, punctuality and rigour. I am also a teamwork enthusiast, able to communicate and cooperate with others to reach a common goal. During my PhD, I have worked under pressure and made decisions in stressful environments to respect deadlines and set objectives, producing work of scientific importance.

Education

- **PhD in Astrophysics** at Astronomy Centre, University of Sussex, United Kingdom [2017 to date] PhD focused on numerical aspect of the Epoch of Reionization, this involve the use of radiative transfer and N-body simulation. At the moment I am implementing the sub-grid inhomogeneity of large box $(500 \, Mpc/h)$, sample size of $O \sim 10^6$) inferring sub-grid distribution from smaller, high resolute simulation $(5 \, Mpc/h)$, sample size $O \sim 10^9$), for the C2-Ray code.
- MSc in Astrophysics at Ludwig-Maximillians-University LMU Munich, Germany [2015 2017] Research master's degree on the effect of large scale structure correlation on the halos cluster count. With the help of semi-analytical N-body simulation I studied the statistical error of clusters number counts due the finite size of the measured Fourier mode of the power spectrum.
- **BSc in Physics & Mathematics** at University of Fribourg UNIFR, Switzerland [2011 2014] Combined degree with major in Physics (150 ECTS) and minor in Mathematics (30 ECTS). Varying topics were discussed, from atomic physics to spectroscopy and an introduction to N-body problem, alongside with advance differential analysis, linear algebra and statistical methods with following practical laboratory for a total of 12 month long experiment.

Scholarship & Grants

• Member of the Royal Astronomical Society RAS

since 8 Feb. 2018

• STFC astronomy research grants (3.5 years)

from 27 Sep. 2017 until 21 Mar. 2021

Skills

I have acquired a number of essential skills that support my current research:

• High Performaces Computers:

I am working with a series of Supercomputers, part of the PRACE Consortium.

- JURECA, Jülich Research on Exascale Cluster Architectures JSC	[started Jan. 2019]
- JUWELS, Jülich Wizard for European Leadership Science JSC	[started Jan. 2019]
- Piz Daint, Swiss National Supercomputer Centre CSCS	[ended Feb. 2018]
- MareNostrum IV (2017), Barcellona Supercomputing Centre BSC	[ended Feb. 2018]
- APOLLO Cluster, permanent account at the University of Sussex	[started Set. 2017]

• Coding languages:

Python (NumPy, Pandas, SciKit, TensorFlow, Keras), C/C++, Fortran, HTML/CSS, Java, Batch Script

• Astronomical and Scientific tools:

DS9, TopCat, Aladin Sky Atlas

LaTex, R, Matlab, Wolfram Mathematica, Maple (2017)

[2013-2014]

• Languages:

- Italian: Native Language
- English: IELTS (6.5/9, B2), test date: June 27, 2015
- French: Advanced level (school, academic year at UNIFR)
- German: Advanced level (school, academic years at LMU and UNIFR)
- Slovenian: understanding and use of common words (personal interest)
- Mandarin: recognise and understanding of basic kanji (personal interest)

Publications & Collaborations

- Impact of inhomogeneous subgrid clumping on cosmic reionization, arXiv: under publication Yi Mao, J. Koda, P. R. Shapiro, I. T. Iliev, G. Mellema, H. Park, K. Ahn and M. Bianco
- Model Sub-grid density inhomogeneity of large simulation for EoR, arXiv: under publication Michele Bianco, I. T. Iliev

Employment

• University of Sussex:

- Assistant tutor, Introduction to Astrophysics	[Winter Semester 2018]
Led problem-solving workshop and marked the undergraduate year	
- Assistant tutor, Mathematical Methods for Physics	[Winter Semester 2018]
Led problem-solving workshop and marked the undergraduate year	

• Swiss Army:

- On duty as soldier, Fusilier Battalion 30/3, Recruit Company 11-3/1	[2014-2015]
Fulfilment of the required military service	

• University of Fribourg:

Led problem-solving workshop for bio-physics undergraduate year	
- Assistant tutor, <i>Practical Laboratory</i> for first year	[2013-2014]
Led practical experiment workshop for bio-physicist undergraduate year	

- Physic Students Council Cashier

- Assistant tutor, *Physics I & II* exercises

Conferences & Workshops

- PRACE Winter School 2019, Introduction to Machine Learning for Scientists, Belgium, 2019
- Parallel and GPU Programming in Python, PRACE training held by SURFsara, the Netherlands, 2018
- GPU Programming with CUDA, PRACE training held by EPCC at Imperial College London, UK, 2018
- South Coast Cosmology, gave a talk, UK, 2018
- RAMSES User Meeting 2018, organized by the Centre de Recherche Astrophysique Lyon, France, 2018
- LOFAR-EoR Plenary Meeting 2018, Groningen, Netherlander, 2018
- MPI, OpenMP and Advanced Topics in Parallel Programming, held by HLRS Stuttgart, Germany, 2017

References

Professor Ilian T. Iliev,
PhD supervisor, University of Sussex
I.T.Iliev@sussex.ac.uk

• Professor Philipp Aebi President physic department (2014), University of Fribourg philipp.aebi@unifr.ch

• Professor Jochen Weller Master thesis supervisor, University Observatory Munich jochen.weller@usm.lmu.de